Register of the Erasmus-Feit family papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Erasmus-Feit family papers
1887-1956
77110
Hoover Institution Archives
5 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box. (3.3 linear feet)
Correspondence, scrapbooks, memorabilia, printed matter, and photographs relating to the daily lives of Russian émigrés in China and the United States, and family matters.
Erasmus-Feit family.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1977.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Family of Baron Erasmus-Feit, Russian Imperial army officer.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, scrapbooks, memorabilia, printed matter, and photographs relating to the daily lives of Russian émigrés in China and the United States, and family matters.
Lebedeva, Nataliia Leonidovna.; Russians--China.; Russians--United States.
- Family File, 1887-1955
  - Lebedeff-Dunkel (nee Sklifosovskaia), Natali'a Viktorovna file, 1901-1949
    - Biographical file, 1901-1920 (Box-folder 1: 1)
      Scope and Contents note
      Includes birth certificate and resident certificate.
    - Correspondence, 1915-1939
      - General, 1915-1937
        - 1915-1918 (Box-folder 1: 2)
        - 1919 (Box-folder 1: 3)
        - 1920 (Box-folder 1: 4)
        - 1921-1924 (Box-folder 1: 5)
        - 1937 (Box-folder 1: 6)
      - Chechovich, Vladimir, circa 1917 (Box-folder 1: 7)
      - Konrad, Iosif (Josiph), 1920 (Box-folder 1: 8)
      - Korff, T., 1929 (Box-folder 1: 9)
      - Kudriashev, Vladimir, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 1: 10)
      - Kurovskii, Vikentii, circa 1915 (Box-folder 1: 11)
      - Osetinskii, Lev (Leo), 1937-1939 (Box-folder 1: 12)
      - Pashenkov, Nikolai, 1920 (Box-folder 1: 13)
      - Sklifosovskaia, Aleksandra Evgen'evna (mother), 1922-1926 (Box-folder 1: 14)
      - Sokolova, Lialia, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 1: 15)
    - Diary, 1918-1936 (Box-folder 1: 16)
    - Photographs, 1902-1922 (Box-folder 1: 17)
    - Scrapbooks, 1914-1949
      Includes invitations, business cards, receipts, and notes.
      - 1914 (Box-folder 2: 1)
      - 1915-1916 (Box-folder 2: 2)
      - 1918-1919 (Box-folder 2: 3)
      - 1933-1949 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Pervushina (Vort), Nina Nikolaevna file, 1948-1955 (Box-folder 2: 5)
    Includes correspondence and photographs of Don Cossack Choir of Serge Jaroff.
  - Sklifosovskaia (nee Feit), Aleksandra Evgen'evna file, 1887-1925
    - Career file, 1900-1924 (Box-folder 2: 6)
      Includes correspondence, notes, and photographs pertaining to Aleksandra Evgen'evna's teaching career.
    - Diaries, 1888-1900 (Box-folder 3: 1-2)
    - Education file, 1892 (Box-folder 3: 3)
      Includes elementary school report, notes, and printed matter.
    - Photographs, 1892-1925
      Depictions of Aleksandra Evgen'evna, her family, and friends, and places.
      - 1892-1900 (Box-folder 3: 4)
      - 1901-1905 (Box-folder 3: 5)
      - 1908-1909 (Box-folder 3: 6-7)
      - 1913-1914 (Box-folder 3: 8)
      - 1916-1917 (Box-folder 3: 9)
      - 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3: 10)
      - 1921-1925 (Box-folder 3: 11)
    - Scrapbooks, 1887-1918 (Box-folder 4: 1-2)
  - Sklifosovskii, Viktor Fedos'evich file, 1897-1921
    - Career file, 1906-1921 (Box-folder 4: 3-5)
      Includes "Posluzhnoi spisok," as well as reports, notes, and other materials relating to Viktor Fedos'evich's military career.
    - Notebook, 1897 (Box-folder 4: 6)
    - Photographs, 1899-1905 (Box-folder 4: 7-8)
      Depictions of Viktor Fedos'evich, his family, and friends.
- General File, 1899-1956
  - Clippings, 1919-1956 (Box-folder 4: 9)
    Includes clippings from Russian language newspapers relating to political, social, and economic conditions in Russia. See also: Box 6.
  - Photographs, 1899-1950
    - Beininia, A. and M., 1907 (Box-folder 4: 10)
    - Denisov family, 1904-1916 (Box-folder 4: 11)
    - Kunguroff, E., 1899-1904 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - Malavsky, Sergei, 1939 (Box-folder 5: 2)
    - Peltier, George, circa 1950 (Box-folder 5: 3)
    - Ponamarev, Nikolai, 1912 (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - Russian peasant wedding in Mexico, 1936 (Box-folder 5: 5)
    - Vavivch, Mikhail Ivanovich, 1930 (Box-folder 5: 6)
    - Vertinskii (Vertinsky), Aleksandr Nikolaevich (negatives), circa 1930 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Postcards, 1904-1950 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Printed matter, 1900-1956
    - Concert and theater programs, 1917-1939 (Box-folder 5: 9)
    - Flirt tsvetov, card game, circa 1900 (Box-folder 5: 10)
    - Marache's Manual of Chess, by N. Marache, New York, 1900 (?) (Box-folder 5: 11)
    - Menestrel', by Igor' Severianin, Berlin, 1921 (Box-folder 5: 12)
    - Sovetskoe Izobrazitel'noe Iskusstvo, by S. Donskoi, Munich, 1956 (Box-folder 5: 13)
    - Kommininisticheskaia Utopiia i Sovetskaia Deistvitel'nost', by Iu. I. Mishalov, Munich, 1937 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - White Emigre organizations files, 1947-1951
    - Cossack's Ass'n., Inc., 1947-1949 (Box-folder 5: 15)
      Includes correspondence and Kazachii Istoricheskii Kalendar' na 1949 god.
    - Zagranichnyi Soiuz Russkikh Voennykh Invalidov, 1947-1951 (Box-folder 5: 16)
      Includes reports, correspondence, and printed matter.
- Oversize Material, 1912-1932
  - Clippings, 1920-1932 (Box-folder 6: 1-3)
  - Erazmus-Feit, Tatiana file, 1912-1914 (Box-folder 6: 4-5)
    Includes Pokhval'nyi list, issued by Nikol'sko-Ussuriiskaia zhenskaia gimnaziia.